hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski in this podcast I talk
about ways for coaches trainers course
creators to increase their sales clients
and make more money in their businesses
now today I want to talk about doing
hard things and here's why cuz I know we
all do hard things but can I tell you
this that when it comes to building our
business there's a different level I
think that we got to take it to life is
hard if you're living on planet Earth
you know that right I don't need to I
don't need to tell you that twice we
live in a crazy economy right now where
things are not necessarily how we would
want them to be um and so as business
owners we got to choose to do the hard
things you know they say that necessity
is the mother of invention being able to
come up with new ways to do things I'll
tell you this is that often times if we
are waiting until we feel ready to do
something we will keep waiting forever
and and I want to tell you this from the
perspective of of my journey myself I
have
struggled
um for a long time
with doing the things that I know that I
need to do in my
business
um because I don't feel ready yet to do
them and and I'll say this for years
this has been the case if I look back at
my entire career even we going on 22
years that I've been in in my career
since 2003 we're almost 22 years it's 21
years
and like I have just put off and put off
and put off the thing that I know that I
need to do until L now listen I made a
lot of
money I've been very successful
financially I've made a ton of money for
our clients I've had a great career
great
business and yet I know that I can do
more I know that I got way more
potential I know that I'm not living up
to that level and if you're listening to
this right now I would be willing to bet
that you feel the same way that you see
where you could
be that you see where you want to
be and you know that you're not there
yet and that's why you keep listening to
podcasts like this I want to tell you a
framework that I believe can help you
with this number one we have to take a
look at what is beneath the surface as
to why we're not doing those things that
we need to do as to why we are
choosing to not do what we must
do it's because we are caught up in our
head with what we should do now let me
explain this to
you the should do that we keep telling
ourselves well I should be doing this I
should be doing that they actually keep
us stuck feeling like we're not
measuring up and when you can learn to
have self compassion kindness towards
yourself you will unlock far more of
your potential and your ability to
accomplish great
things let me explain this to you a
little bit deeper for myself
I find that if I constantly focus on
what is not working what's not going how
I want what I wish was different what I
think should be
different and
I
am I'm focused on the wrong things when
I'm thinking about that my creativity
gets stifled my ability to think well
about what I need to be doing what I
must be doing gets limited by well I
should have done this I should have done
that I should have but I
haven't I can even look at on a
day-to-day basis feeling guilty for what
I'm not doing what I am
doing
and letting this take over
me doesn't have to be that
way and I'll I'll tell you this the
number one thing that has helped me is
getting to the root of where that comes
from for me it came from perfectionism
it came from the need to do
everything perfect and as coaches and
mentors we make a living pointing out
what people need to be doing better and
yet we
are a double-edged sword the most
critical of ourselves when we need to be
very kind to
ourselves you know I can look at for the
last six months knowing what I should be
doing but the reason why every single
time that I didn't do that and
procrastinated was because of being
harsh on what I should be doing rather
than just giving myself the grace to
have fun enjoy the process go through
things and and I and I'll tell you I
have had Cycles in my life I've had
Cycles where I'm I'm everything is
firing on all cylinders where I'm doing
all the stuff that I need to be doing
where I'm doing everything that I must
be doing my fitness is in order my
business my all of my activities are in
order and by the way can I tell you this
your income and your results in your
business is usually a lagging indicator
of what you're doing for the last 6
months and so you might be doing all the
right things but you might not see the
results of it for 6 months from now
don't become weary in that learn to be
consistent learn to stay
consistent even if you don't see the
returns
immediately knowing that you're doing
the right things and here's what I look
back at I look back at in my life the
times when things were going really well
for me what was I doing in those moments
what did my day-to-day look like what
did my day-to-day activities look like
and then I start modeling that in how I
am living and operating in my life I can
look back at uh in my business the very
best season that I ever had was uh
between August
2022 and January 2023 and my son was
born in January 2023 now again I'm not
blaming my family but I'll tell you I
have had to relearn how to do life and
business with
family and I can tell you now today
that I feel more
confident my marriage isn't the best
place it's ever been my family life is
amazing my business is firing on all
cylinders and we're in the best spot
possible and so I know and I model I
modeled it after what were the habits
that I was doing during that time
period you know I think if we can look
back at what our habits were during the
best time periods of our life what were
we thinking what were we focusing on
what was our Behavior like what did our
day-to-day activities look like what
were we doing differently then that
we're not doing now and then what have
we learned now that we didn't have then
I'll tell you this two years ago I was
terrified at what everybody thought
about me today not not at all like
truly feel so at ease with other
people's opinions me and and I talked
about this two years ago like you can't
you can't let other people's opinions of
you stop you why because I was in it I
was deeply in it and it was hurting
me it was keeping me stuck where I
needed to go was escaping me because I
was constantly worried about what
everybody would think about me did they
think I was a good dad did they think I
was a good husband did they think I was
a good business owner did they think
that I was doing all the right things in
my business they judging me for my
opinions on artificial intelligence and
all this stuff and all of that was
festering in my
mind keeping me from operating at the
level of my
potential letting other people's
opinions needing to measure up perfectly
to what everybody else was thinking and
I'll tell you I tried it doesn't work
never has never will learn to let go of
what everybody else thinks about you and
start thinking positively about
yourself and I want to tell you what
that looks like that looks like
believing that you're the best in the
world of what you do and you're the only
one that can do it the way that you do
it and you might say Jeremiah that
sounds really
arrogant no it's
not
again existentially I know there are
people they are more skilled and better
than me at a lot of stuff but I am the
only one version of me that's out there
and I am the best at what I do every
single
day now again we can't get caught up in
this cycle of like I people people like
I can't think that because then it's
going to make me feel like I don't need
to improve can I tell you
this if you're actually somebody who
takes personal development seriously
you're going to improve no matter what
so you might as well think really really
really highly of yourself
and then see things start to come
together better for you and I'll tell
you this what I just said right now
might be challenging some of what you
have been taught or have learned in your
life up to this moment in time you might
have even judged other people who think
highly of themselves as I will never be
that
way it's one of the biggest things that
can create breakthrough in our lives the
level of your your income is limited by
how much you believe in your greatness
it
is because you will not operate and act
as somebody who can produce the kind of
income that you want to make unless you
believe that you are that type of
person and so what we have to do is we
have to
believe we become we
be and then we start operating and
acting as that person and then we have
have the results that we want in our
life you know a lot of people think that
if I can just do all the right things
then I will be that person and this is
such an a a a backwards way of
thinking because who we are does not
come from or is not defined by what we
have done or have
accomplished it comes from within every
single time and so this is why
in your life if you find yourself not
living up to your
potential it starts with what's going on
up here it starts with believing in
yourself it starts with
knowing that you
have an
unlimited ability to do whatever you
want to you can accomplish whatever you
want now let's design our life how we
want to accomplish let's design our life
in the way that we know is going going
to
work you know I had a man about 6 months
ago argue with me that all of this was
BS that I just
said and since then he's left my life
because he disrespected he just he
just just didn't like what I'm sharing
and and here's what I would say to him
I'll say
this how's that working out for you
you've been doing the same thing for 19
years with no results
I'll tell you
this the people who call what I'm saying
BS they're not living the life that they
want and every time that I look at when
I have not been living the life that I
want I have been in self-critical
thinking hyper fixed on perfectionism
doing all the right things saying it all
perfectly instead of learning to give
myself Grace compassion
self-love believing in myself
fully even if the evidence in my life
doesn't show
it still believing
it every single day and learning to
operate as
if I have already accomplished
everything
that I want to now I'll tell you this I
have an incredible track record in my
life and yet I struggle with this isn't
that
crazy so I can tell you this as somebody
who has a track record that when my
beliefs
shift I don't operate as the man that I
am I don't operate as the
person that I am meant to be I am
operating only to the level of those
beliefs you know I used to have this
belief
that I that I only rise to the level of
my last greatest mistake and how you do
one thing is how you do everything and I
can tell you this that thinking defined
me and put me into a hole and a mental
prison for over a year and a
half constantly beating myself up over
the mistakes that I was
making as a parent as a husband in my
business
and now I can tell you that I have
freedom from that that I'm not living
and operating in a
framework of needing to do everything
perfect that I am embracing making
mistakes on a regular basis and not
letting those things dominate me not
beating myself up but learning to be
calm collected excited controlling my
nervous system
and giving myself the grace that I
deserve loving myself through the
struggle if you can learn to do what
I've just talked about here on this
podcast your entire life will shift your
entire life will change you won't be
operating in the past you won't be
operating in the struggle
and you'll be able to start to rise
above whatever mistakes you've ever had
can I tell you this you are greater than
any mistake you've ever
had and all of your dreams can become a
reality they can be
accomplished but you got to believe it
you got to believe you're capable of it
right now with what you got right now
you might be saying well Jeremiah I
don't have the skills I don't have the
resources I don't have the talent I
don't have the connections I don't have
the track record and
testimonies those things we only think
they matter when we don't have
them and I can tell you as somebody who
didn't and does that if I knew what I
know
today 22 years
ago my life would be in a different
place it
would hindsight's
2020 but what I can do is instead of
being upset about
that create the best future in tomorrow
for myself and my family and you can do
the
same you don't have
to stay stuck where you are right now at
the level that you're at right
now you can accomplish
incredible
exceptional greater than you've ever
imagined
things now you got to go in and do the
work you got to take what I just talked
about and start building your landing
pages start creating your marketing
campaigns start marketing your business
from the perspective of believing in
your greatness
and not
letting your fears and worries and
doubts and insecurities Define
you and start
living in a new dimension a new reality
I tell you this I believe that there are
multiple dimensions and realities in our
future that are possible for us and we
get to choose which one we want to walk
in we can literally shift the timeline
in our life we we can literally learn to
shift our entire
reality through our thoughts our beliefs
and our what we declare in our
lives you know there's a couple of great
books I've been reading lately one of
them is called The Game of Life and how
to play it by Francis
Goin read that one multiple times found
it really incredible and one of the
things is this is learning to
surrender and live in love
love and grace and
peace and not being so attached to well
I need it to go this way for me or
else when we can do that and then you
start to build out the things in your
business and you start to learn to let
go of trying to control what people
think about you trying to control how
the campaign goes maybe you're
struggling with your Facebook ads maybe
you want them to work but you're feeling
Jaded by the fact that you didn't get
the exact result last time when you ran
your ads it's time to rise above what
happened last time it's time to do the
thing that you fear the most it's time
to step out it's time to walk in faith
it's time to take a risk and see what's
possible for you it's time to say no
more to the fear and worry that is
stopping
us you can do great things I believe it
I know it
do you believe it yourself because
that's what you need to do is I can
believe so much for you but you got to
believe it
yourself and you might want to keep Rel
listening to this podcast episode
anytime you feel stuck anytime you feel
down write it down save the episode
number come back to it and see what
happens all right everybody listen I
hope this has blessed you share this p
this on to
somebody and watch what happens in your
life and theirs grow your life everybody
and we'll talk soon have a good
[Music]